Miller, Frank B., Files /4210
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Frank B. Miller Files
1970-1984
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Miller, Frank B.
/4210
3 cubic feet
3 linear ft.
Records (documents).
ILR lecture notes, files from the Balance of State Manpower Council, correspondence, and book drafts.
8051467
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, June 16, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Frank Miller, ILR professor emeritus and Cornell mace bearer, dies at 84
Frank B. Miller Jr., professor emeritus at the School of Industrial and Labor Relations (ILR) and expert on organizational behavior who carried Cornell's mace for 20 years at university events, died March 2 at Cayuga Medical Center in Ithaca. He was 84.
A memorial mass and celebration of Miller's life was held in Anabel Taylor Hall chapel March 10.
Miller joined the ILR School faculty in 1954 as an assistant professor after completing his Ph.D. there and undergraduate studies in psychology at Reed College. He became associate professor in 1960 and professor in 1966.
During his 31 years as a faculty member, Miller taught courses on a range of subjects, including complex organizations; small groups in industrial organizations; and applied human relations. He also designed the first course on women in the workplace at the ILR School and co-taught it with colleague Alice Cook, a world-renowned expert on issues faced by working women. In addition, Miller chaired the organizational behavior department for several years (1967-69) and served two terms as director of the school's Office of Resident Instruction (1962-67).
As a visiting professor at the University of Istanbul in 1960-61, Miller gave lectures that were translated into Turkish and became a textbook for personnel studies courses there. He also contributed chapters to books on industrial sociology and worker incentives and was a fellow of the American Sociological Society and the Society of Applied Anthropology.
Although he attained emeritus status in 1985, Miller continued teaching part time at Cornell and Bernard Baruch College in New York City for another 10 years.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of lecture and course notes for ILR 44: Human Relations; ILR 192: Industrial Plants; ILR 360: Human Resource Economics and Public Policy; ILR 467: Women at Work. Also included are minutes and files from the Balance of State Manpower Council, as well as correspondence and drafts for the book Historical Sources of Personnel Work, an Annotated Bibliography of Developments to 1923.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4259: Frank B. Miller Corning Glass files /4297: ILR School Biography Files /4308m: Frank Miller ILR School Poetry /4311: Frank Miller Papers 6401: Mortimer Gellis Insurance Workers International Union Papers
Miller, Frank B.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations
8051467
- Rehabilitation, Sheltered Workshops, and the Disadvantaged (Box 1, Folder 1)
- BOS/CETA General Materials (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Effectiveness of MP Training U.S.GPO - Joint Economic Committee (Box 1, Folder 3)
- BOS Planning Council (Box 1, Folder 4)
- BOS Manpower Planning Council Meetings and Minutes (Box 1, Folder 5)
- BOS Meeting, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Scope and Contents
  November 1974
- Indian Manpower Prog. Proposed (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Center for Minority Studies (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Rural Manpower Proposal (Box 1, Folder 9)
- CCC '77 Selection, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- C.C.C. (C.C.) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- (Frank Miller) The Rural Manpower Training Service Prog. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Rural Manpower Project Ed Smith (Box 1, Folder 13)
- "Balance of State" Report to C. Moser, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  July 1974
- Manpower-Rehab Contract Summer Research Forms (Box 1, Folder 15)
- "Turnover in Schoharie" Rural Manpower (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Regional Manpower Training Center (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Current Hitchhike Proposals, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Sheltered Workshop Budget (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Tompkins County Manpower Plan, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Manpower Practioner's MILR - Potential Faculty (Box 1, Folder 21)
- ILR360 Fall '84, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Xerox Corporation E. E. O. Seminar Workshop (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Research Materials (Box 1, Folder 24)
- ILR 467 Spring 1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- ILR 192 Lecture (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Human Relations Research in Corning Glass Works (Box 2, Folder 3)
- The Soviet Union's Search for Labor Resources (Box 2, Folder 4)
- An Independent Sector Assessment of the Job Training Partnership Act (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Sexual Harassment (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Child Care and Equal Opportunity for Women (Box 2, Folder 7)
- His Copy Of It (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Women Workers Win One in New York (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Unsorted (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Sex and the Personnel Manager (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Women in Personnel (Box 2, Folder 12)
- AHL HR Notes (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Letters (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Unsorted Historical Material (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Misc. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- General Schema (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Correspondence re History of Pers (book) (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Personnel History Material (Box 3, Folder 6)
- General Schema (Box 3, Folder 7)
- "General" Personnel Package (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Seminar (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Correspondence re Research Bulletin (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Correspondence re Bibliography (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Long Reviews of Reference Texts and Theses (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Financial Welfare (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Non-Financial Welfare (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Assorted Welfare Material (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Vacations (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Papers On (Box 3, Folder 17)
- EE Rep (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Record Keeping (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Cartoons (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Permission to Reproduce (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Tables of Contents (Box 3, Folder 22)
- British Personnel History (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Bibliographies (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Barnard, Chester (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Cooke, Morris (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Henry Duflon (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Carroll E. French and Ind. Rel. Counselors (Box 3, Folder 28)
- General Electric Crotonville (Box 3, Folder 29)
- J. J. Jehring (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Ling - Indiana (Box 3, Folder 31)
- National Industrial Conf. Board (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Robert Ozanne (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Procter and Gamble Co. (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Radom, Matthew (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Nathan W. Shefferman (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Milton thesis (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Shefferman, Nathan - Material (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Wage - Salary (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Eugene J. Benge (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Society for Advancement of Mgmt. (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Correspondence Thomas Spates (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Ordway Tead (Box 3, Folder 43)